Mike Wallace Papers
Mike Wallace Papers
1959-1961
Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012.
14 linear feet
Papers of the television journalist and news commentator. Television documentary, interview scripts and audiorecordings of interviews. People represented include Edward Albee, Cleveland Amory, George Axelrod, William F. Buckley Jr., Marcel Duchamp, Max Eastman, Anne Francis, Gus Hall, Ben Hecht, Henry Kissinger, Shirley MacLaine, Bishop James A. Pike, Ayn Rand, Carl Sandburg, Gore Vidal, and Tennessee Williams.
148732
Biographical History
Myron Leon "Mike" Wallace (1918-2012) was an American journalist, interviewer, actor, host and commentator.
Born in Brookline, Massachusetts on May 9, 1918, he received his Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of Michigan after attending the University from 1935 to 1939. Wallace first appeared on radio as a regular guest on the quiz show Information Please in 1939, and began the transition to television work in 1949. During his early career, Wallace hosted the television interview programs Night Beat on WABD-New York (1955-1957),The Mike Wallace Interview on ABC (1957-1958), PM East for Westinghouse Broadcasting (1961-1962), and the David Wolper-produced Biography series in the early 1960s. In 1959, Wallace co-produced with Louis Lomax a five-part documentary on the Nation of Islam, The Hate That Hate Produced. After hosting The CBS Morning News for many years, in 1968 Wallace began his long tenure on the CBS News program, 60 Minutes, where he served as a host and corresponsdent for the next forty years of his career. Over the course of his distinguished career, Wallace received many awards and recognitions, including 21 Emmy Awards, 3 Alfred I. duPont-Columbia University Awards and 3 George Foster Peabody Awards. In 2003 he was awarded a Lifetime Achievement Emmy.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Mike Wallace Papers consists of transcripts and audiorecordings of interviews with a wide variety of personalities, including authors, entertainers, religious leaders, political figures, and more. Notable interviewees include Edward Albee, Cleveland Amory, George Axelrod, William F. Buckley Jr., Marcel Duchamp, Max Eastman, Anne Francis, Gus Hall, Ben Hecht, Henry Kissinger, Shirley MacLaine, Bishop James A. Pike, Ayn Rand, Carl Sandburg, Gore Vidal, Tennessee Williams, and many more. The collection also contains the 1959 documentary on the Nation of Islam, The Hate That Hate Produced in film (telecine) and videotape formats.
Although the collection may contain both script(s) and audiorecording(s) for a given person, they are not necessarily from the same interview. A complete index of all interview participants is available at the end of this finding aid.
Other Formats Available
All recordings in the collection have been digitized. Please contact the repository listed above for more information.
Arrangement of the Collection
Scripts are arranged alphabetically by interviewee. Audiorecordings are in order by ID number.
Related Material
The University of Michigan, Wallace's alma mater, holds the majority of Mike Wallace's papers. The University of Texas at Austin's Harrry Ransom Center has a video collection of Wallace interviews, accessible at http://www.hrc.utexas.edu/collections/film/holdings/wallace/.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Popular culture; Journalism; Wallace, Mike, 1918-2012.; Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967.; Vidal, Gore, 1925-2012.; Williams, Tennessee, 1911-1983.; Albee, Edward, 1928-; Amory, Cleveland.; Axelrod, George.; Buckley, William F., Jr., 1925-2008.; Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Francis, Anne, 1932-2011.; Hall, Gus.; Hecht, Ben, 1894-1964.; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; MacLaine, Shirley, 1934-; Pike, James A. (James Albert), 1913-1969.; Rand, Ayn.; Serling, Rod, 1924-1975.; The hate that hate produced.; Politicians -- Interviews.; Actors -- Interviews.; Actresses -- Interviews.; Authors -- Interviews.; Comedians -- Interviews.; Journalists -- United States.; Documentary film.; Film reels.; Interviews.; Sound recordings.; Transcripts.; Videotapes.; Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Interview scripts
  Although the collection may contain both script(s) and audiorecording(s) for a given person, they are not necessarily from the same interview. A complete index of all interview participants is available at the end of this finding aid.
  - Aadland, Beverly, Nov 10 1959 (Box 1)
  - Aherne, Brian, Apr 1 1960 (Box 1)
  - Albee, Edward, Feb 15 1961 (Box 1)
  - Albert, Eddie, Jan 17 1961 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Mel, May 12 1959 (Box 1)
  - Allen, Steve, Oct 10 1960 (Box 1)
  - Amory, Cleveland, Dec 10 1959; Dec 5 1960,; Dec 19 1960 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Dana, Apr 6 1959 (Box 1)
  - Anka, Paul, Nov 22, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Ashmore, Harry, May 19 1960 (Box 1)
  - Atkinson, Ted, Mar 4 1959 (Box 1)
  - Aumont, Jean Pierre, Mar 10 1960 (Box 1)
  - Axelrod, George, Mar 30 1960; Apr 20 1960 (Box 1)
  - Baldwin, James, Mar 24 1961 (Box 1)
  - Balin, Ina, Sep 13 1960 (Box 1)
  - Bancroft, Anne, Mar 6 1959 (Box 1)
  - Baxley, Barbara, Nov 21 1960 (Box 1)
  - Bean, Orson, Mar 18 1959 (Box 1)
  - Beatty, Clyde, Apr 9 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bedford, Duchess of, Oct 25 1960 (Box 1)
  - Begin, Menachem, Nov 28 1960 (Box 1)
  - Belfrage, Sally, Mar 23 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bendix, William, Oct 31 1960 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Tony, Mar 29 1961 (Box 1)
  - Berman, Shelley, Apr 20 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bikel, Theodore, Nov 20 1959 (Box 1)
  - Blansherd [Blanshard?], Paul, Jan 14 1960 (Box 1)
  - Block, Martin, Mar 12 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bloeth, Jane, Aug 17 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bonomi, John, Dec 20 1960 (Box 1)
  - Boswell, Connee, Dec 19 1960 (Box 1)
  - Bowles, Chester, Dec 17 1959 (Box 1)
  - Boyington, Pappy, May 5 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bracken, Eddie, Sep 16 1959 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, William, Apr 13 1959 (Box 1)
  - Branden, Nathaniel, Feb 29 1960 (Box 1)
  - Bricktop, Mar 3 1961 (Box 2)
  - Brooks, Mel, Jan 17 1961 (Box 2)
  - Bucholz, Earl, Feb 9 1961 (Box 2)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., Dec 5 1960; Feb 29 1960 (Box 2)
  - Burnett, Carol, Mar 17 1960 (Box 2)
  - Caldwell, Erskine, Nov 6 1959 (Box 2)
  - Calloway, Cab, Sep 24 1959 (Box 2)
  - Calvert, Captain James, Nov 1 1960 (Box 2)
  - Campanella, Roy, Nov 27 1959 (Box 2)
  - Carey, James B, Oct 29 1959 (Box 2)
  - Carnera, Primo, Mar 10 1961 (Box 2)
  - Carroll, Diahann, Feb 10 1961 (Box 2)
  - Cassevetes,John, Oct 31 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cassini, Oleg, Jan 6 1961 (Box 2)
  - Cater, Douglass, Oct 4 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cerf, Bennett, Nov 19 1959 (Box 2)
  - Channing, Carol, Mar 3 1961 (Box 2)
  - Charell, Lissa, Apr 1 1960 (Box 2)
  - Chase, Ilka, Oct 10 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cobb, Lee J., May 10 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Alexander, Dec 4 1959 (Box 2)
  - Cohen, Benjamin, Jun 17 1959 (Box 2)
  - Comden, Betty and Green, Adolph, Feb 17 1961 (Box 2)
  - Conniff, Frank, Jan 6 1961 (Box 2)
  - Conreid, Hans, Feb 24 1959 (Box 2)
  - Cousy, Bob, Sep 16 1959 (Box 2)
  - Cowles, Fleur, Oct 15 1959 (Box 2)
  - Cox, Wally, Oct 5 1959 (Box 2)
  - Crawford, Christina, Sep 19 1960 (Box 3)
  - Crawford, John, Aug 17 1959 (Box 3)
  - Crawford, Kenneth, Nov 7 1960 (Box 3)
  - Crosby, Gary, Mar 23 1961 (Box 2)
  - Crosby, John, Oct 28 1959; Nov 7 1960 (Box 2)
  - Crowther, Bosley, Apr 3 1960 (Box 2)
  - Cugat, Xavier, Mar 30 1959 (Box 3)
  - Dahl, Roald, n.d. (Box 3)
  - D'Amato, Gus, May 12 1959 (Box 3)
  - Danielsen, Terry, Jul 23 1959 (Box 3)
  - Darcel, Denise, Nov 4 1959 (Box 3)
  - Darin, Bobby, May 31 1960; Mar 16 1961 (Box 3)
  - Dash, Samuel, Nov 4 1959 (Box 3)
  - Dauphin, Claude, Mar 3 1960 (Box 3)
  - Davis, Sammy, Jr., Mar 2 1959; Dec 28 1960 (Box 3)
  - Day, Dorothy, Sep 9 1959 (Box 3)
  - Dee, Ruby, Mar 30 1961 (Box 3)
  - DeHaven, Gloria, Nov 14 1960 (Box 3)
  - Demara, F.W., Jul 7 1959 (Box 3)
  - Desai, Morarji, Oct 4 1960 (Box 3)
  - DeSeversky, Alexander, Apr 22 1960 (Box 3)
  - de Toledano, Ralph, Apr 29 1960 (Box 3)
  - Diller, Phyllis, Oct 17 1960 (Box 3)
  - Douglas, Jack, Apr 6 1959 (Box 3)
  - Douglas, Melvyn, Oct 9 1959 (Box 3)
  - Downs, Hugh, Sep 12 1960 (Box 3)
  - Duchamp, Marcel, Dec 12 1960 (Box 3)
  - East, P.D, Mar 10 1961 (Box 3)
  - Eastman, Max, Apr 13 1959 (Box 3)
  - Edmondson, J. Howard, Oct 26 1959 (Box 3)
  - Ellis, Dr. Albert, Mar 26 1959 (Box 3)
  - Emerson, Faye, May 30 1960 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Maurice, Nov 20 1959 (Box 3)
  - Fabian, Sep 26 1960 (Box 4)
  - Falkenberg, Jinx, Aug 24 1959 (Box 4)
  - Feiffer, Jules, Mar 30 1960 (Box 4)
  - Fitzgerald, Ed, Jan 8 1960 (Box 4)
  - Fletcher, Joseph, Oct 3 1960 (Box 4)
  - Foch, Nina, Oct 12 1959 (Box 4)
  - Ford, Phil and Hines, Mimi, Jan 12 1961 (Box 4)
  - Francis, Anne, Sep 15 1959 (Box 4)
  - Francis, Arlene, Feb 24 1959 (Box 4)
  - Francis, Connie, Nov 16 1960 (Box 4)
  - Frank, Gerold, Mar 18 1959 (Box 4)
  - Furness, Betty, Oct 1 1959; Mar 10 1961 (Box 4)
  - Gabor, Eva, Jun 10 1959 (Box 4)
  - Gabor, Jolie, Jul 2 1959 (Box 4)
  - Gabor, Zsa Zsa, Feb 9 1961 (Box 4)
  - Galento, Tony, May 1 1959 (Box 4)
  - Gang Leader, Sep 30 1959 (Box 4)
  - Gardner, Hy, Apr 22 1959 (Box 4)
  - Gerlich, Jackie, May 1 1959 (Box 4)
  - Gifford, Frank, Mar 9 1961 (Box 4)
  - Gillespie, Dizzy, Mar 23 1961 (Box 4)
  - Gonzalez, Pancho, Apr 15 1959 (Box 4)
  - Graham, Sheilah, Feb 23 1959 (Box 4)
  - Granville, Joseph, Dec 12 1960 (Box 4)
  - Gray, Robert K., Feb 3 1961 (Box 4)
  - Greco, Jose, Apr 15 1960 (Box 4)
  - Greene, Gael, Apr 17 1960 (Box 4)
  - Gregory, Dick, Apr 10 1961 (Box 4)
  - Griffin, John Howard, Mar 22 1960 (Box 4)
  - Griffith, Andy, May 5 1959 (Box 4)
  - Guttmacher, Alan, Jul 29 1959 (Box 4)
  - Haigh, Kenneth, Mar 10 1960 (Box 5)
  - Hall, Gus, Dec 17 1959; Jan 6 1961 (Box 5)
  - Hansberry, Lorraine, May 8 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hardwicke, Sir Cedric, Apr 2 1959 (Box 5)
  - Harriman, Averell, Jul 27 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hart, Moss, Oct 28 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hartford, Huntington, May 12 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hauser, Gayelord, Jan 26 1961 (Box 5)
  - Havoc, June, Feb 25 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hayakawa, Sessue, Apr 20 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hecht, Ben, Mar 23 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hildegarde, Nov 5 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hilgemeier, Ed, Aug 10 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hillary, Sir Edmund, Aug 3 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hingle, Pat, Jan 14 1960 (Box 5)
  - Hodges, Luther, Apr 14 1961 (Box 5)
  - Hoffmann, Dr. Richard, Feb 21 1961 (Box 5)
  - Horwich, Frances, Sep 16 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hughes, Emmet John, Nov 5 1959 (Box 5)
  - Huie, William Bradford, Mar 16 1959 (Box 5)
  - Humphrey, Hubert, Mar 9 1959 (Box 5)
  - Hunter, Kim, Apr 30 1961 (Box 5)
  - Hutchinson, Admiral Elmo, Dec 10 1959 (Box 5)
  - Irwin, Monte, Mar 14 1960 (Box 6)
  - Isaacs, Stanley, Dec 23 1959 (Box 6)
  - Israel Interviews (opens and closes) (Box 6)
  - Jaffe, Rona, Sep 21 1959 (Box 6)
  - Jessel, George, Aug 31 1959 (Box 6)
  - Jorgensen, Christine, Apr 22 1959 (Box 6)
  - Kenny, Nick, Oct 30 1960 (Box 6)
  - King, Dennis, Mar 2 1961 (?) (Box 6)
  - King, Martin Luther, Feb 2 1961 (Box 6)
  - Kinkead, Eugene, Mar 18 1959 (Box 6)
  - Kintner, Earl, Feb 16 1960 (Box 6)
  - Kissinger, Henry, Mar 2 1961 (Box 6)
  - Kitt, Eartha, Jun 17 1959; Apr 14 1961 (Box 6)
  - Kline, Nathan, Mar 10 1960 (Box 6)
  - Koch, Leo F., Nov 16 1960; additional informational material (Box 6)
  - Laine, Frankie, Apr 15 1959 (Box 6)
  - Lanchester, Elsa, Aug 31 1959; Feb 23 1961 (Box 6)
  - Landis, James M., Jan 11 1961 (Box 6)
  - Lane, Abbe, Mar 30 1959 (Box 6)
  - Lane, Frank, Jan 24 1960 (Box 6)
  - Lanphier, Thomas, Jun 2 1960 (Box 6)
  - Laurence, William L., Oct 2 1959; May 30 1960 (Box 6)
  - Laurie, Piper, Jan 24 1960 (Box 6)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., Dec 30 1959 (Box 6)
  - Lemmon, Jack, Oct 31 1960 (Box 6)
  - Leonard, Jack E., Mar 25 1960 (Box 6)
  - Leonetti, Tommy, Mar 23 1959 (Box 6)
  - Lerner, Max, Oct 10 1960 (Box 6)
  - Levin, Meyer, Sep 28 1959 (Box 7)
  - Levy, Raoul, Sep 23 1959 (Box 7)
  - Leyra, Camilo Weston, Apr 2 1959 (Box 7)
  - Lilo, Nov 14 1960 (Box 7)
  - London, Ephraim, Apr 28 1959 (Box 7)
  - Loos, Anita, Apr 6 1961 (Box 7)
  - Lorre, Peter, Feb 17 1960 (Box 7)
  - Louis, Joe, May 26 1960 (Box 7)
  - Louise, Tina, Mar 2 1960 (Box 7)
  - Lovejoy, Frank, Apr 14 1960 (Box 7)
  - Loy, Myrna, Oct 17 1960 (Box 7)
  - Lumet, Sidney, Feb 25 1960 (Box 7)
  - Lynley, Carol, Mar 3 1961 (Box 7)
  - Lytess, Natasha, Nov 21 1960 (Box 7)
  - MacDonald, Jeanette, Aug or Sept 1959 (Box 7)
  - Machado, China, Mar 21 1961 (Box 7)
  - Maclver, Joyce, Feb 3 1961 (Box 7)
  - MacLaine, Shirley, Nov 23 1959 (Box 7)
  - Mailer, Norman, Nov 18 1959 (Box 7)
  - Malden, Karl, Mar 17 1961 (Box 7)
  - Mankowitz, Wolf, Mar 16 1960 (Box 7)
  - Mannes, Marya, Apr 3 1960; Oct 25 1960 (Box 7)
  - March, Hal, Mar 9 1961 (Box 7)
  - Mason, Pamela, Dec 26 1960 (Box 7)
  - Maurois, Andre, Nov 16 1960 (Box 7)
  - Maxwell, Elsa, Apr 14 1961 (Box 7)
  - McBride, Mary Margaret, Dec 13 1960 (Box 7)
  - McDonald, Marie, Apr 6 1959 (Box 7)
  - McDowell, Roddy, Apr 14 1961 (Box 7)
  - McKay, Gardner, May 19 1960 (Box 7)
  - McManus. Virginia, n.d. (Box 7)
  - McVey, Jackson, Apr 3 1960 (Box 7)
  - Meacham. Anne, Nov 28 1960 (Box 7)
  - Meadows, Jayne, Mar 26 1959 (Box 7)
  - Medina, Harold, Sep 2 1959 (Box 7)
  - Menon, V.K. Krishna, Nov 6 1959 (Box 7)
  - Merriam, Eve, Nov 7 1960 (Box 7)
  - Merrick, David, Jan 12 1961 (Box 7)
  - Mesta, Perle, Apr 14 1960 (Box 7)
  - Meyer, Frank, Jan 5 1961 (Box 7)
  - Michelfelder, William, Oct 3 1960 (Box 7)
  - Michener, James, Sep 27 1960 (Box 8)
  - Mineo, Sal, May 10 1960; Sep 19 1960 (Box 8)
  - Montagu, Ashley, Sep 13 1960 (Box 8)
  - Mr. John, Apr 28 1959 (Box 8)
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm, Sep 26 1960 (Box 8)
  - Mulligan. Gerry, Jul 1 1959 (Box 8)
  - Murray, Ken, Feb 11 1960 (Box 8)
  - Murray, Mac, Nov 18 1959 (Box 8)
  - Myerson, Bess, Oct 18 1960 (Box 8)
  - Nagel, Conrad, Oct 16 1959 (Box 8)
  - Newmar, Julie, Apr 15 1959; Feb 23 1961 (Box 8)
  - Nichols, Mike, Dec 20 1960 (Box 8)
  - Novarro, Ramon, Nov 27 1959 (Box 8)
  - Obolensky, Serge, Mar 30 1959 (Box 8)
  - O'Brien, Margaret, Mar 9 1961 (Box 8)
  - Odero-Jour, J.G., Nov 16 1960 (?) (Box 8)
  - O'Keefe, Dennis, Sep 15 1959 (Box 8)
  - O'Leary, Frank, Jul 9 1959 (Box 8)
  - Pasternak. Joseph, Oct 30 1959 (Box 8)
  - Pauling, Linus, Dr., Oct 24 1960 (Box 8)
  - Paxinou, Katina, Oct 5 1959 (Box 8)
  - Pernot, Dom Placide, Sep 19 1960 (Box 8)
  - Petrovskaya, Kyra, May 8 1959 (Box 8)
  - Pike, Bishop James A., Feb 21 1961 (Box 8)
  - Pincus, Gregory, Dr., Nov 22 1960 (Box 8)
  - Poston, Tom, May 22 1959 (Box 8)
  - Powell, Adam C., Mar 16 1959 (Box 8)
  - Preminger, Otto, Jun 23 1959; Jan 12 1961 (Box 8)
  - Prinz, Joachim, Jan 8 1960 (Box 8)
  - Quill, Michael J., Apr 22 1959; Sep 26 1960 (Box 8)
  - Rand, Ayn, Feb 25 1959; Apr 18 1960,; Mar 17 1961 (Box 8)
  - Randall, Tony, Sep 2 1959 (Box 8)
  - Randell, Ron, Aug 5 1959 (Box 8)
  - Randolph, A. Philip, Oct 21 1959 (Box 8)
  - Regler, Gustav, Mar 3 1960 (Box 8)
  - Remick, Lee, Aug 26 1959; Jan 27 1960 (Box 9)
  - Reuther, Walter, Oct 4 1960 (Box 9)
  - Reynolds, Quentin, Sep 27 1960; n.d. (Box 9)
  - Rich, Buddy, Sep 3 1959; Dec 6 1960 (Box 9)
  - Riesel, Victor, Oct 23 1959; Dec 28 1960 (Box 9)
  - Ritchard, Cyril, Apr 14 1961 (Box 9)
  - Robbins, Dr. Lewis, Feb 10 1961 (Box 9)
  - Robustelli, Andy, Apr 11 1961 (Box 9)
  - Rocca, Antonino, Apr 22 1960 (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt Jr., Franklin D. Jr., May 25 1959 (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt, James, May 25 1959 (Box 9)
  - Roosevelt Jr., Mrs. Theodore, Jul 24 1959 (Box 9)
  - Rosenfeld, Henry, Nov 8 1960 (Box 9)
  - Rosensohn, William, Jun 23 1959 (Box 9)
  - Rosten, Leo, Oct 7 1959 (Box 9)
  - Roth, Philip, Mar 28 1960 (Box 9)
  - Ruark, Robert, Sep 1959 (?) (Box 9)
  - Rule, Janice, Apr 11 1961 (Box 9)
  - Sahl, Mort, Apr 6 1960 (Box 9)
  - St. John, Robert, Oct 18 1960 (Box 9)
  - Salisbury, Harrison, Oct 22 1959 (Box 9)
  - Sandburg, Carl, Sep 12 1960 (Box 9)
  - Schary, Dore, Mar 16 1961 (Box 9)
  - Scopes, John T, Oct 10 1960 (Box 9)
  - Scott, Hazel, Apr 14 1961 (Box 9)
  - Scott, Zachary, Feb 2 1961 (Box 9)
  - Seal, Elizabeth, Jan 12 1961 (Box 9)
  - Seberg, Jean, Mar 17 1961 (Box 9)
  - Segal, Harry "Champ", Feb 15 1961 (Box 9)
  - Serling, Rod, Sep 15 1959 (Box 9)
  - Sheean, Vincent, Mar 7 1960 (Box 9)
  - Sherek, Henry, Dec 30 1959 (Box 9)
  - Shirer, William, Nov 29 1960 (Box 9)
  - Shor, Toots, May 15 1959 (Box 9)
  - Sillman, Leonard, Oct 23 1959 (Box 9)
  - Skinner, Cornelia Otis, Oct 2 1959 (Box 9)
  - Smith, H. Allen, Mar 14 1960 (Box 9)
  - Smith, Merriman, Feb 10 1961 (Box 10)
  - Sokolsky, George, Mar 9 1960 (Box 10)
  - Soraci, Carmelo, Apr 6 1961 (Box 10)
  - Soustelle, Jacques, Mar 30 1960 (Box 10)
  - Stapleton, Maureen, May 1 1959 (Box 10)
  - Steiger, Rod, Nov 22 1960 (Box 10)
  - Sterling, Jan, Mar 16 1960 (Box 10)
  - Stern, Bill, Oct 9 1959 (Box 10)
  - Stern, Isaac, Jan 12 1961 (Box 10)
  - Stevens, Inger, Dec 20 1959 (Box 10)
  - Stevens, Leslie, Apr 6 1960 (?) (Box 10)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, Sep 14 1959 (Box 10)
  - Stone, Willis, Oct 11 1960; additional informational material (Box 10)
  - Stritch, Elaine, Mar 12 1959 (?) (Box 10)
  - Styne, Jule, Mar 2 1960 (Box 10)
  - Susskind, David, Apr 28 1959; Sep 20 1960 (Box 10)
  - Taylor, Renee, Jan 6 1961 (Box 10)
  - Tillstrom, Bur, Nov 8 1960 (Box 10)
  - Todd, Mike Jr., Feb 11 1960 (Box 10)
  - Torme, Mel, Feb 17 1961 (Box 10)
  - Tracy, Vincent, Jan 5 1961 (Box 10)
  - Trapp, Maria, Dec 6 1960; Dec 20 1960 (Box 10)
  - Umeki, Myoshi, Apr 20 1959 (Box 10)
  - Uphaus, Willard Dr., dec 13 1960 (Box 10)
  - Ustinov, Peter, Jul 21 1959 (Box 10)
  - Vallee, Rudy, Jul 14 1959 (Box 10)
  - Vanderbilt, Amy, Nov 25 1959 (Box 10)
  - Van Dyke, Dick, Feb 17 1961 (Box 10)
  - Van Fleet, General James, Jun 9 1959 (Box 10)
  - Van Horne, Harriet, Apr 29 1960 (Box 11)
  - Van Rensselaer, Philip, Apr 15 1960 (Box 11)
  - Veeck, Bill, Jan 24 1960 (Box 11)
  - Vidal, Gore, May 8 1959; Apr 18 1960,; Dec 12 1960,; Dec 13 1960 (Box 11)
  - Vidie, Ambassador D., Mar 17 1960 (Box 11)
  - Wagner, Robert F., Jan 25 1960 (Box 11)
  - Walcott, Jersey Joe, Aug 1959 (?) (Box 11)
  - Walker, Nancy, Feb 3 1961 (Box 11)
  - Wallach, Eli, Dec 4 1959; Jan 26 1961 (Box 11)
  - Waters, Ethel, Apr 9 1959 (Box 11)
  - Waugh, Alec, Apr 8 1960 (Box 11)
  - Wechsler, James, May 23 1960 (Box 11)
  - Wertham, Dr. Frederic, Jan 28 1960; Apr 25 1960,; Nov 1 1960 (Box 11)
  - Wheeler, Bert, May 5 1959 (Box 11)
  - Whiteman, Paul, May 18 1960 (Box 11)
  - Williams, Governor G. Mennen, Apr 15 1959 (Box 11)
  - Williams, Tennessee, Nov 14 1960 (Box 11)
  - Winters, Jonathan, Mar 25 1960 (Box 11)
  - Wismer, Harry, Nov 8 1960 (Box 11)
  - Wiznitzer, Louis, Oct 18 1960 (Box 11)
  - Wyman, Louis, Dec 19 1960 (Box 11)
  - Youngman, Henny, Jan 26 1961 (Box 11)
  - Zolotow, Maurice, Apr 4 1960; Nov 14 1960 (Box 11)
- Interview audiorecordings
  All recordings in the collection have been digitized. Please contact the repository listed above for more information.
  - Dr. Fredric Wertham (1), Feb 1960; wallace_m_001; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - William F. Buckley, Jr., 03/07/1960; wallace_m_002; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:40 (Oversize 1)
  - Peter Lorre, 03/08/1960; wallace_m_003; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 26:46 (Oversize 1)
  - Tina Louise, 03/09/1960; wallace_m_004; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 23:58 (Oversize 1)
  - William Workman, 03/01/1960; wallace_m_005; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:52 (Oversize 1)
  - Claude Dauphin, 03/11/1960; wallace_m_006; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - Jule Styne, 03/14/1960; wallace_m_007; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:52 (Oversize 1)
  - Dr. Fredric Wertham (2), 03/15/1960; wallace_m_008; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:53 (Oversize 1)
  - Vincent Sheean, 03/16/1960; wallace_m_009; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:53 (Oversize 1)
  - Jean Pierre Aumont, 03/17/1960; wallace_m_010; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:52 (Oversize 1)
  - Nathaniel Branden, 03/18/1960; wallace_m_011; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 23:52 (Oversize 1)
  - George Sokolsky - Part 1, 03/21/1960; wallace_m_012; reel tape, 7", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:53 (Oversize 1)
  - George Sokolsky - Part 2, 03/22/1960; wallace_m_013; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - Kenneth Haigh, 03/23/1960; wallace_m_014; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - William Bradford Huie, 03/24/1960; wallace_m_015; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - Dr. Nathan Kline, 03/25/1960; wallace_m_016; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 26:53 (Oversize 1)
  - Jonathan Winters, wallace_m_017; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:52 (Oversize 1)
  - Jan Sterling, 03/30/1960; wallace_m_018; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 26:19 (Oversize 1)
  - Wolf Mankowitz, 03/31/1960; wallace_m_019; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:48 (Oversize 1)
  - Earl Kintner, wallace_m_020; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - Harry Allen Smith, wallace_m_021; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 24:58 (Oversize 1)
  - Brian Aherne, wallace_m_022; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Jackson McVey, wallace_m_023; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - John Howard Griffin, wallace_m_024; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 27:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Mort Sahl, 04/06/1960; wallace_m_025; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 29:00 (Oversize 1)
  - Jacques Soustelle, wallace_m_026; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:49 (Oversize 1)
  - Carol Burnett, wallace_m_027; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 24:19 (Oversize 1)
  - Gustav Regler, wallace_m_028; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 24:47 (Oversize 1)
  - Lissa Charell, wallace_m_029; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:58 (Oversize 1)
  - Bosley Crowther, wallace_m_030; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:52 (Oversize 1)
  - Maurice Zolotow, wallace_m_031; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:55 (Oversize 1)
  - Marya Mannes, wallace_m_032; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 26:05 (Oversize 1)
  - Leslie Stevens, wallace_m_033; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:46 (Oversize 1)
  - Dobrivije Vidic, wallace_m_034; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:45 (Oversize 1)
  - Jack E. Leonard, wallace_m_035; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 26:58 (Oversize 1)
  - Alec Waugh, wallace_m_036; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 1)
  - Jose Greco, wallace_m_037; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 23:50 (Oversize 2)
  - Perle Mesta, wallace_m_038; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 23:45 (Oversize 2)
  - Jules Feiffer, wallace_m_039; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 28:30 (Oversize 2)
  - Frank Lovejoy, wallace_m_040; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 27:30 (Oversize 2)
  - Antonio Rocca, wallace_m_041; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 26:30 (Oversize 2)
  - George Axelrod, wallace_m_042; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 27:30 (Oversize 2)
  - Ayn Rand, wallace_m_043; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 25:12 (Oversize 2)
  - Gore Vidal, wallace_m_044; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 24:22 (Oversize 2)
  - Harriet Van Horne, wallace_m_045; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 24:54 (Oversize 2)
  - Ralph de Toledano, wallace_m_046; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 24:49 (Oversize 2)
  - Major Alexander P. DeSeversky, wallace_m_047; reel tape, 1/4", 7 1/2 ips; running time 24:23 (Oversize 2)